If you look through the media player documentation, you'll find this method,
当你查阅 MediaPlayer 文档时 你会发现这个方法
setOnCompletionListener.
setOnCompletionListener
So the description says here that this method
这里的说明指出该方法
allows you to register a callback.
允许你注册一个回调
They'll be called when the end of the media source or
当媒体资源或音频文件到达结束位置时
audio file has been reached.
会回调该方法
Notices that the input of this method is an on completion listener.
注意该方法的输入是 OnCompletionListener
So let's click into it for more details.
点开来看看详情
So MediaPlayer.OnCompletionListener is an interface.
MediaPlayer.OnCompletionListener 是个接口
So that means you'll need to implement it and
意味着你需要实施该方法
provide the code for it's onCompletion() method.
并为其 onCompletion() 方法提供代码
So the answer to this first question is that the onCompletion() method
第 1 个问题的答案是：当 MediaPlayer 停止播放媒体文件时
of the onCompletionListener object will be called
onCompletionListener 对象的
when the MediaPlayer has finished playing the media file.
onCompletion() 方法将被调用
And then in step number two, I asked you to use this information.
在第 2 步 我请你使用该信息
To modify the music player sample app.
修改 MusicPlayer 示例应用
So that when the song is done playing, a toast message pops up.
当歌曲停止播放时 系统会弹出提示消息
So let's go back to our music player project in Android Studio.
我们回到 Android Studio 中的 MusicPlayer 项目
So after the media player started,
在 MusicPlayer 开始后
I'm going to set up a callback to be notified when the song is done.
我将设置一个回调 以便当歌曲停止播放时获得通知
And as noted in the quiz hint we provided you, we need to set up
根据我们提供的测试题提示
the completion listener after the media player has started.
在 MusicPlayer 开始后 我们需要设置 completionListener
So after mediaPlayer.start is called,
当 mediaPlayer.start() 被调用后
let's call the set on completion listener method.
我们来调用 setOnCompletionListener 方法
So inside this method I'm going to define an anonymous listener class
我将在这个方法内定义一个行内匿名 listener 类
in line and remember that it's anonymous because I'm not giving it a class name.
匿名是指我不会为其设定一个类名
So there's no need to give it a class name here.
所以这里没必要为其设定一个类名
Because I'm only going to be using this class definition once.
因为我只使用该类定义一次
Now inside the onCompletion method I'm going to modify it so
在 onCompletion 方法内 我将修改下代码
that it pops up a toast message that says, I'm done!
使其弹出提示消息“I'm done!”
All right, so now let's test it, I'm going to hit the play button.
现在来测试下 点按“播放”按钮
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
And when it's done, the toast message pops up.
播放完毕后 弹出一条提示消息
So great work.
很不错
So to summarize, I'm using an asynchronous callback
总结下 我使用了一个异步回调
to get notified when the media player is done playing the song.
当 MediaPlayer 播放完歌曲后 我会获得通知
And in the meantime, I can go about doing other things.
在此期间 我可以执行其他操作
Like respond to other button clicks from the user.
例如对用户的其他按钮点击操作做出响应
All while waiting to get called back.
并等待着获得回调